A rural clinic cannot wait for the cloud.
One health worker may see fifty patients in a day.
The dangerous cases do not always look dramatic at first.
This patient is thirty-two weeks pregnant with bleeding,
abdominal pain, and dizziness.
The worker cannot wait for a network round-trip.
MediScribe does not freeze.
It catches the red flag, explains the danger in plain language,
creates a referral handoff, and saves the visit offline.
Gemma 4 helps rank diagnoses and explain the reasoning.
But the model does not act alone.
Safety rules override routine advice when danger signs appear.
The second hero path is stroke.
When FAST symptoms appear, the app escalates immediately
and structures the handoff while the clock is still on the patient's side.
The workflow matches the clinic:
speak symptoms, scan chart notes, confirm the extracted summary,
and move straight to a safer decision.
One visit is the first layer.
Across many offline visits, clinic leaders can see dangerous patterns:
maternal risk, respiratory clusters, and outbreak signals.
This is a working Gemma 4 system:
local inference through Ollama, offline mobile storage,
deterministic safety checks, public code,
and a published Unsloth adapter trained on curated clinic scenarios.
MediScribe brings local medical intelligence
to the clinic moments where waiting is dangerous.